<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Donald duck voice Archives - How To Do Stuff</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/donald-duck-voice/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/donald-duck-voice/</link>
	<description>How To Do Tips and Tricks - How stuff works</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 12:49:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Donald duck voice Archives - How To Do Stuff</title>
	<link>/tag/donald-duck-voice/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to Sound or Talk Like Donald Duck easily</title>
		<link>/how-to-sound-like-donald-duck-easy/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-sound-like-donald-duck-easy</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Expert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 08:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[How to sound]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to speak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice Mimicry Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[donald duck angry sound]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Duck impression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[donald duck message tone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald duck noises]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald duck oh boy sound]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Duck Phrases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald duck sound]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald duck voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geluid donald duck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to talk like donald duck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[make kids laugh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sound like donald duck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sounding Like Donald duck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[speak like donald duck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trick to impress friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voice of Donald Duck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=583</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>You can talk like Donald Duck to impress friends and make kids laugh. You just need to perfect the voice of Donald Duck and make use some of Donald&#8217;s trademark quotes or sayings. Anyone can talk like Donald duck, it just require some practice to achieve the sound of Donald duck. How to Talk/Sound Like &#8230; <a href="/how-to-sound-like-donald-duck-easy/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-sound-like-donald-duck-easy/">How to Sound or Talk Like Donald Duck easily</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">How To Do Stuff</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You can <a href="/tag/how-to-talk-like-donald-duck/">talk like Donald Duck</a> to impress friends and make kids laugh. You just need to perfect the <a href="/tag/voice-of-donald-duck/">voice of Donald Duck</a> and make use some of Donald&#8217;s trademark quotes or sayings. Anyone can <a href="/tag/how-to-talk-like-donald-duck/">talk like Donald duck</a>, it just require some practice to achieve the <a href="/tag/sound-like-donald-duck/">sound of Donald duck</a>.</p>
<h4><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-593" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/how-to-sound-like-donald-duck.jpg" alt="How to sound like donald duck" width="1000" height="562" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/how-to-sound-like-donald-duck.jpg 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/06/how-to-sound-like-donald-duck-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/06/how-to-sound-like-donald-duck-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></h4>
<h4>How to Talk/Sound Like Donald duck</h4>
<ol>
<li><em><strong>Put your tongue to the roof of your mouth.</strong> </em>Open your teeth slightly. Place your tongue so the top of your tongue is lightly touching the roof of your mouth.</li>
<li><em><strong>Twist your tongue a little to the left or right.</strong> </em>Go with whatever direction feels more comfortable to you. Put the side of your tongue slightly inside the space between your upper and lower teeth.</li>
<li><strong><em>Press your tongue.</em></strong> Push your tongue against the inside of the teeth on the side of your mouth. Use enough pressure that the tongue remains in contact with the teeth, but loose enough that you can push air between your tongue and teeth.</li>
<li><strong><em>Vibrate your tongue.</em></strong> Blow air and direct it into the cheek that your tongue is on. Use your cheek to push the air through the gap behind or between your teeth and your tongue. When you push the air through properly, you will hear a high-pitched, hoarse sound.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ul>
<li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ul>
<li>Try pushing the air through different spaces between your tongue and your teeth until you hit a good spot. It might be difficult at first to make the sound consistently, but keep at it. Getting this voice down will require strengthening muscles of your mouth your aren&#8217;t used to using for speaking.</li>
<li>Be patient. It took the current actor that plays Donald Duck a full year of training to get the voice right.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li><strong><em>Form words as you would with your own voice.</em></strong> Most of the work in changing your voice should be done with your mouth, not your vocal cords. If you are feeling any soreness in your throat you should take a break. Talking like Donald, especially attempting a long Donald Duck rant, takes a lot of breath and can make you light-headed. Even the voice actor that plays Donald needs a break after a long rant so be sure you don&#8217;t overdo it.
<ul>
<li>To make the angry Donald sound make the normal Donald noise while shaking your head so your cheeks flap and vibrate the sound.</li>
<li>Some letters are easier to say than others. For example, when Donald Duck says the word little, it sounds like widdle. Changes to letter pronunciation will come naturally as a limitation to speaking in his voice.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<h4>Using Donald Duck Phrases</h4>
<ol>
<li><em><strong>Use Donald Duck expressions.</strong> </em>&#8220;Boy, oh boy!&#8221; This is one of the most common expressions used by Donald Duck and can be heard in most of his dialogues. It can be added on to the beginning of most sentences and can express a wide range of emotions.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li style="list-style-type: none;">Use some of Donald&#8217;s other favorite words continually. Donald also likes to ask the question, &#8220;What&#8217;s the big idea?&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li><em><strong>Have a lot of tantrums.</strong> </em>Donald is a famously cranky duck that gets angry over just about anything. Work on making angry Donald Duck noises. Try making an angry quacking noise while doing the Donald Duck voice.</li>
<li><em><strong>Inflect your voice like Donald Duck.</strong> </em>Donald Duck speaks in an animated way. Listen to some clips of Donald speaking and pay attention to the pitch and tone of his voice. When he is excited he tends to speak faster in a much higher pitch. When he is sad the pitch drops and his speech slows down.</li>
</ol>
<p>Also Read: <a href="/how-to-sound-smarter/">How to Sound Smarter</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-sound-like-donald-duck-easy/">How to Sound or Talk Like Donald Duck easily</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">How To Do Stuff</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
