<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Exercise Archives - How To Do Stuff</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/exercise/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/exercise/</link>
	<description>How To Do Tips and Tricks - How stuff works</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 09:37:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Exercise Archives - How To Do Stuff</title>
	<link>/category/exercise/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to do push ups at home for female beginners</title>
		<link>/push-ups-at-home-tips-for-female-beginners/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=push-ups-at-home-tips-for-female-beginners</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Expert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 10:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exercise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Female fitness workout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Push-up workout for females]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strength Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Workout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Best ways to do push ups at home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Building strength]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Core workout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Female beginners workout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Female pushup exercise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Female workout steps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[get started with pushups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gym]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Home exercise push ups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Home push up workout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Home training push ups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to do push-ups for female beginners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incline pushups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kneeling pushups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[push ups at home step by step]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[push ups for beginners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[push ups for female beginners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Push ups workout at home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[push-up tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pushup tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pushup variations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pushups at home steps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pushups for females]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Standard pushups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Standing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wall pushups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=96</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Push up tips for female beginners at home In this article, we have explained how to do push-ups for female beginners to Build the muscles in your shoulders and chest with this foundational exercise. This push up exercise targets arms, chest, core and shoulders. How to do Push ups for female beginners at home : &#8230; <a href="/push-ups-at-home-tips-for-female-beginners/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/push-ups-at-home-tips-for-female-beginners/">How to do push ups at home for female beginners</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">How To Do Stuff</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-100 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/push-up.jpg" alt="How to do push ups at home for beginners" width="1000" height="333" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/push-up.jpg 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/push-up-300x100.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/push-up-768x256.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></p>
<h3>Push up tips for female beginners at home</h3>
<p>In this article, we have explained how to do push-ups for female beginners to Build the muscles in your shoulders and chest with this foundational <a href="/category/exercise/">exercise</a>.</p>
<p><strong>This push up exercise targets</strong> arms, chest, core and shoulders.</p>
<h3>How to do Push ups for female beginners at home : Basic Steps</h3>
<p><strong>1.</strong> Get down on all fours, placing your hands slightly wider than your shoulders.</p>
<p><strong>2.</strong> Straighten your arms and legs.</p>
<p><strong>3.</strong> Lower your body until your chest nearly touches the floor.</p>
<p><strong>4.</strong> Pause, then push yourself back up.</p>
<p><strong>5.</strong> Repeat.</p>
<p>Pushups are a simple and effective bodyweight movement that can help increase strength in your upper body and core. This <a href="/category/exercise/">exercise</a> works the pectoral muscles in your chest and the triceps. These are the muscles in the back of your upper arms.</p>
<p>You don’t need any equipment to get started with pushups. They’re suitable for <a href="/category/beginners-guide/">beginners</a> and individuals who are more advanced with exercise.</p>
<h4>Progressing to pushups</h4>
<p>While you may be familiar with standard pushups, there are many variations that may help you get started, progress, or increase difficulty.</p>
<p>Try doing a set of 10 to 15 of each exercise, rest, and then do another set of 10 to 15.</p>
<blockquote class="css-pc7ote"><p>Performing fewer pushups with correct form will be better over time than completing many with poor form.</p></blockquote>
<p>Here are five pushup variations that increase in difficulty.</p>
<h3>Wall pushups</h3>
<p>Doing a standing pushup against the wall is a good starting place if you’re new to this move. By standing, you put less pressure on your joints.</p>
<ol>
<li>With your feet shoulder-width apart, stand about an arm’s length away from a wall.</li>
<li>Place your palms on the wall as you lean forward into a standing plank position. Your arms should be shoulder height and shoulder-width apart.</li>
<li>Inhale as you bend your elbows and slowly move your upper body toward the wall while keeping your feet flat on the ground.</li>
<li>Hold this position for a second or two.</li>
<li>Exhale and use your arms to push your body slowly back to your starting position.</li>
</ol>
<div class="css-1pkj7lb">
<div class="css-zr4wb2">
<h3 class="css-1v0jij4">Change it up</h3>
<div class="css-pzg5fr">
<p class="standout--body">As you get more comfortable, you can try one-handed wall pushups. Follow all the instructions above, but alternate sets by placing one arm bent behind you with the outside of your hand on the small of your back. You could also alternate keeping one arm at your side as you pushup with the other.</p>
<p>To work on stability in your shoulders, try pushups from a seated position.</p>
<ol>
<li>Sit on a bench with your palms down, arms at your side. Your feet should rest comfortably on the ground with your knees bent.</li>
<li>Using your arms, push down into your palms so that your body lifts up — still in the seated position. Your hips and butt should be just a half inch or so off the bench.</li>
<li>Lower back down to your starting position and repeat.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Kneeling pushups</h3>
<div class="css-0">
<p>Balancing on your knees instead of your feet is another good modification while you build your strength.</p>
<ol>
<li>Begin in a hands and knees position with your gaze at the floor.</li>
<li>Place your hands on the ground on either side of your shoulders. Your knees should be at a comfortable distance apart.</li>
<li>Inhale as you slowly lower your elbows to bring your chest toward the ground. Be sure to keep your core muscles contracted.</li>
<li>Pause for a second in the lowered position — your chin may lightly touch the ground.</li>
<li>Exhale as you push up from the ground to your starting position.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote class="css-pc7ote"><p>Another way to start this pushup is to begin by laying on your stomach. Bend your knees so your feet are up in the air, then push with your hands into position on your knees.</p></blockquote>
<h3>Standard pushups</h3>
<p>Fully extending your legs increases the difficulty of this move by adding more body weight. One study showed that the “ground reaction force” or how much weight you push is 64 percent of your body weight with standard pushups. To compare, a kneeling pushup is 49 percent.</p>
<ol>
<li>Begin with your chest and stomach flat on the floor. Your legs should be straight out behind you and your palms should be at chest level with the arms bent out at a 45-degree angle.</li>
<li>Exhale as you push from your hands and heels, bringing your torso, chest, and thighs off the ground.</li>
<li>Pause for a second in the plank position — keep your core engaged.</li>
<li>Inhale as you slowly lower back to your starting position.</li>
</ol>
<div class="css-1pkj7lb">
<div class="css-zr4wb2">
<div>
<h3 class="css-1v0jij4">Change it up</h3>
<div class="css-pzg5fr">
<p class="standout--body">Another great variation of the standard pushup is a pushup with hip abduction. Follow the same instructions as a standard pushup, but lift your left leg off the ground as you lower. Move it slightly further out than your hips and keep your foot flexed. Then repeat on the other side after switching legs from the plank position.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="css-1enc0ig"></div>
</div>
<h3>Incline pushups</h3>
<p>If you want to really challenge your upper body, try incline pushups. You’ll need a stable surface on which to place your hands.</p>
<ol>
<li>Place your hands on the edge of the elevated surface. A bench, step, or other sturdy platform are good options.</li>
<li>Step your feet back so your legs are straight and your arms are perpendicular to your body.</li>
<li>Inhale as you slowly lower your chest to the edge of your platform.</li>
<li>Pause for a second.</li>
<li>Exhale as you push back to your starting position with your arms fully extended.</li>
</ol>
<p>You can further increase difficulty by using a medicine ball, BOSU or balance ball, or suspension trainer. Doing so will make your body work harder to stabilize, taxing muscles even more.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="hl-incontent-video-ad" class="css-1sxbpyw" data-adbridg-ad-class="hl-incontent"><span style="font-size: 32px; font-weight: bold; letter-spacing: -0.0415625em;">Tips and more modifications</span></div>
</div>
<div class="css-0">
<h3>Comfort measures</h3>
<p>Try these methods to make your pushups more comfortable.</p>
<ul>
<li>Perform pushups on a yoga mat or similar surface instead of a bare floor.</li>
<li>When doing kneeling pushups, place a folded towel under your knees for extra cushioning.</li>
<li>To avoid wrist pain, place hands directly under shoulders with your fingers pointing directly in front of you.</li>
<li>Place palms flat on the floor versus cupping your hands. This avoids straining your hands.</li>
<li>Look down at the ground during this exercise to avoid straining your neck.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Overall form</h3>
<p>When doing pushups on the ground, you’ll want to keep a flat back. Resist sagging your spine or arching it up toward the ceiling. Contracting your core muscles will help keep your form in check. Make sure to keep your movements slow and controlled versus slamming your body down too quickly. Your shoulders, hips, and ankles should be aligned.</p>
<h3>Hand positioning (narrow vs. wide)</h3>
<p>You might wonder how hand positioning might increase difficulty. Your options are holding your hands wide apart or more narrowly together. To incorporate hand positioning into your routine, try keeping your palms in front of your chest and your elbows in toward your body at the start of your pushups.</p>
<h3>Building strength</h3>
<p>Pushups may be hard to complete at first, even with modification. If you cannot complete 10 to 15, start with sets of 5 or less and build from there.</p>
<p>Increasing strength and endurance takes time but is worth the effort. Remember, performing fewer pushups with correct form will be better over time than completing many with poor form.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
<div class="css-0">
<h4>The takeaway</h4>
<p>After you get the hang of pushups and are confident with your form, you may want to try a pushups challenge. Consistency is important to building strength. In the challenge, you work your way up over the course of 2 months until you can complete 100 pushups at one time.</p>
<p>Even if you’re not looking to go so extreme, incorporating this efficient body-weight exercise into your routine is sure to strengthen your upper body, back, and core to help with everyday movement.</p>
<p><strong>Also Read:</strong></p>
<p><a href="/how-to-boost-your-immunity/">How to boost immunity naturally</a></p>
<p><a href="/how-to-beat-burnout-exhaustion-stress/">How to prevent burnout</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/push-ups-at-home-tips-for-female-beginners/">How to do push ups at home for female beginners</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">How To Do Stuff</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
