<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Sound smarter at work Archives - How To Do Stuff</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/sound-smarter-at-work/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/sound-smarter-at-work/</link>
	<description>How To Do Tips and Tricks - How stuff works</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 09:23:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Sound smarter at work Archives - How To Do Stuff</title>
	<link>/tag/sound-smarter-at-work/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Ways to Sound Smarter than you really are / How to be an eloquent speaker</title>
		<link>/how-to-sound-smarter/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-sound-smarter</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Expert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 12:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interview Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personality Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self Improvement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[appearing intelligent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[be an eloquent speaker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Be confident while talking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eliminate Pauses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eloquently speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to be eloquent speaker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to be smart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to boost confidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to look smart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to sound smarter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to speak eloquently]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Make Eye Contact]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[make yourself heard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plan Ahead]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read More]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sound smarter at work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sound smarter in meetings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sound Smarter Than You Really Are]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sound smarter when talking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stand Tall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strike a Power Pose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Take control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips for sounding smarter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ways to Sound Smarter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=353</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Tips for sounding smarter with minimal effort / be eloquent while speaking In today&#8217;s competitive business world, it&#8217;s not enough to be smart. You must be able to sway others to agree with you. Coming across as intelligent is one of our main goals every time we open our mouths to speak. Eloquent people sound &#8230; <a href="/how-to-sound-smarter/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-sound-smarter/">Ways to Sound Smarter than you really are / How to be an eloquent speaker</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">How To Do Stuff</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-371" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/How-to-sound-smarter-1024x437.png" alt="How to sound smarter" width="600" height="256" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/How-to-sound-smarter-1024x437.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/04/How-to-sound-smarter-300x128.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/04/How-to-sound-smarter-768x328.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/04/How-to-sound-smarter.png 1296w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></h3>
<h3>Tips for sounding smarter with minimal effort / be eloquent while speaking</h3>
<p>In today&#8217;s competitive business world, it&#8217;s not enough to be smart. You must be able to sway others to agree with you. Coming across as intelligent is one of our main goals every time we open our mouths to speak. Eloquent people sound smart, regardless of how intelligent they are. Eloquence is a skill that can be taught, practiced, and mastered. Here are twelve easily mastered techniques to quickly make yourself more eloquent and smarter sounding.</p>
<h3>How to sound smart / eloquent speaker when talking in meetings at work</h3>
<p><strong> 1. <a href="/tag/plan-ahead/">Plan Ahead</a></strong></p>
<p>Whether you are in a private conversation or at a company-wide town hall, the most important thing you can do is <a href="/tag/make-yourself-heard/">make yourself heard</a>, loud and clear. This can be daunting for an introvert—and for the rest of us. The key is preparation. If you’re interviewing for a job, review the posting and take advantage of the whole googleplex of information about your prospective company. If you’re attending a staff meeting, check the agenda. Going on a date? Plan some talking points, even if they’re just about favourite TV shows or movies. Feeling prepared will put you at ease and <a href="/tag/how-to-boost-confidence/">boost your confidence</a>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-373" title="Listen smart" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/smarter_1-300x216.jpg" alt="Listen smart" width="500" height="360" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/smarter_1-300x216.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/04/smarter_1.jpg 728w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></p>
<p><strong> 2. Listen</strong></p>
<p>It sounds simple, but listening is a major key to <a href="/tag/appearing-intelligent/">appearing intelligent</a>. Don’t feel the need to comment on every single thing people say; chime in on topics you’re knowledgeable about and ask thoughtful questions about ones you’re not. Chances are the person you’re talking to will be more than happy to answer, never realizing you’re out of the loop.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><span dir="ltr"> 3. <a href="/tag/make-eye-contact/">Make Eye Contact</a></span></strong></p>
<p>If someone looks at you <a href="/tag/sound-smarter-when-talking/">while you are talking</a>, you are more likely to think he or she is smart. &#8220;Good eye contact means the other person is responsive to what you are doing or saying,&#8221; says Bogdan Wojciszke, a professor of social psychology at the University of Social Sciences and Hu-manities in Poland. &#8220;If he is not responsive, this means that either you are dull or he is dumb. With such a choice, most of us prefer to think that he is dumb.&#8221; Researchers at Brandeis University in Massachusetts, USA, found that conversationalists who maintained eye contact scored higher on IQ tests than those who avoided someone’s gaze.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong> 4. Stand Tall</strong></p>
<p>What you’re saying is important, but your body language also speaks volumes to your credibility. If you’re slumping, you’re communicating a lack of confidence not only in yourself but also in what you’re saying. On the other end of the spectrum, standing rigidly straight makes you seem nervous and uncomfortable. Shoot for something in the middle.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-375" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/smart_2.jpg" alt="smart" width="728" height="524" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/smart_2.jpg 728w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/04/smart_2-300x216.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong> 5. <span dir="ltr">Strike a Power Pose</span></strong></p>
<p>How open or closed your posture is conveys how open or closed you are to the physical, mental and emotional advances of others. Openness can convey confidence. To project self-assurance in a meeting, adapt an open, expansive pose. Sit up straight and leave your arms widely spread on the table or at your sides. (This also works if you are trying to attract someone’s eye.) If you are worried about projecting confidence, run through a couple of power poses—such as standing with your hands on your hips or using them to lean on your desk—in private beforehand.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong> 6. Cut back on crutch words</strong></p>
<p>Certain words and vocal tendencies are like tics: They’re hard to get rid of and sometimes we do them without even noticing. Words such as “like” and “um” make you sound unsure of yourself&#8211;as do things like uptalk, that inflection where you end your sentence in a higher tone <em>like you’re asking a question?</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><span dir="ltr"> 7. Eliminate Pauses</span></strong></p>
<p>Confidence is as perceptible in your voice as it is in your body language. As you have probably noticed from watching any political panel show or business meeting with multiple speakers, the &#8216;winner&#8217; of the talk is usually the person who speaks most energetically and fluidly. Too many pauses make you sound unsure of yourself. If you are unconvinced by your own ideas, why should the rest of the room be convinced? Theoretical physicist Leonard Mlodinow points out the impact of this bias: &#8220;If two speakers utter exactly the same words but one speaks a little faster and louder and with fewer pauses and greater variation in volume, that speaker will be judged to be more energetic, knowledgeable and intelligent.&#8221;</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-377 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/books.jpg" alt="Read more books" width="800" height="450" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/books.jpg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/04/books-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/04/books-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></p>
<p><strong> 8. <a href="/tag/read-more-books/">Read More</a></strong></p>
<p>Duh, right? But seriously, reading is arguably the most effective way to sound smarter. We’re not saying you have to tackle the unabridged works of Tolstoy, but try to read one long-form article every week: They’re usually rather in-depth, so you’ll come away with a good grasp on an interesting topic. You could also subscribe to an email newsletter that sends you a daily list of important stories summarized in just a few lines.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong> 9. <span dir="ltr">Restate Others’ </span><span dir="ltr">Smart Points</span></strong></p>
<p>Because of one of those unfair-but-true mental quirks, the person in a meeting who simply summarizes the good points made by everyone else will often be better remembered than the people who came up with the ideas in the first place. If you are struggling to get a word in at your next staff gathering, take notes on the best comments your co-workers deliver. Near the end of the meeting, restate these ideas in a concise, matter-of-fact way. Even when giving credit to your co-workers, you will sound smarter.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong> 10. <a href="/tag/take-control/">Take control</a></strong></p>
<p>You’re at a dinner party, and the woman you’re talking to brings up her work in, ack, nuclear astrophysics, we think? Instead of trying to fake your way through a conversation, try to subtly switch gears to something you’re more comfortable with. (“Nuclear astrophysics? Cool, that’s what my freshman roommate studied, but now she’s a SoulCycle instructor. Have you ever tried Soul?”)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong> 11. <span dir="ltr">Tell Some Jokes</span></strong></p>
<p>Women find men they overhear telling funny jokes to be smarter and more attractive than those heard talking about mundane topics. Other studies have shown that funny women similarly appear smarter to others. There may be some validity to this, because a certain level of intellect is required to consistently make clever remarks. According to an article published in The Conversation by Lowri Dowthwaite, lecturer in Psychological Interventions, University of Central Lancashire, UK, evolutionary psychologists describe humour as a &#8220;heritable trait&#8221; that signals mental fitness and intellectual agility to prospective mates. In studies of attractiveness, both men and women rate funny people as more attractive, and cite having a good sense of humour as being one of the most important traits in a long-term partner. So you can use humour as a hard-to-fake cue to your intelligence. Just don’t forget the punchline!</p>
<p><strong> 12. Don’t use SAT words</strong></p>
<p>Using big, intimidating words doesn’t make you sound smarter; it just makes you sound like you’re trying way too<em> </em>hard. It’s akin to when you wrote essays in college and used every inconsequential and superfluous filler word to occupy the vast expanse of unfilled page before of you. (See what we did there?) Instead, use clear, direct words and make your point. It’s far less pretentious, and the people you’re addressing will actually understand what you’re saying.</p>
<p>Also Read:</p>
<p><a href="/how-to-sound-like-donald-duck-easy/">How to Talk/Sound Like Donald Duck</a><br />
<a href="/how-to-beat-burnout-exhaustion-stress/">How to Prevent Burnout at Workspace</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-sound-smarter/">Ways to Sound Smarter than you really are / How to be an eloquent speaker</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">How To Do Stuff</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
