<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Get rid of ants at home Archives - How To Do Stuff</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/get-rid-of-ants-at-home/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/get-rid-of-ants-at-home/</link>
	<description>How To Do Tips and Tricks - How stuff works</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 12:05:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Get rid of ants at home Archives - How To Do Stuff</title>
	<link>/tag/get-rid-of-ants-at-home/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to Get Rid of Ants : Ways to Repel Ants safely</title>
		<link>/get-rid-of-ants-ways-to-repel-ants-safely/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=get-rid-of-ants-ways-to-repel-ants-safely</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Expert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 09:48:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cleaning Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gardening Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Home & Garden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Home Improvement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Household]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hygiene & Safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insect Control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seasonal Cleaning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Get rid of ants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Get rid of ants at home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Get rid of ants permanently]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[get rid of ants without killing them]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[help to get rid of the ants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home remedies to get rid of ants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Household pest control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to avoid ants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to get rid of ants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to prevent ants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to repel ants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keep household clean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[natural ways to eliminate ants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[natural ways to repel ants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Repel ants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Repel Ants safely]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stop ants from entering home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stop kitchen ants]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1144</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ants in your house can be a big nuisance. Here are some really effective home remedies to get rid of ants. They are simple and cost effective. Where there is one ant visible, there are likely thousands more nearby. If an ant infestation occurs in your home, you’ll want to solve the problem fast. Are &#8230; <a href="/get-rid-of-ants-ways-to-repel-ants-safely/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/get-rid-of-ants-ways-to-repel-ants-safely/">How to Get Rid of Ants : Ways to Repel Ants safely</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">How To Do Stuff</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-1166 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/how-to-get-rid-of-ants-in-the-house-1024x576.jpg" alt="How to get rid of ants / Ways to Repel Ants" width="600" height="338" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/how-to-get-rid-of-ants-in-the-house-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/10/how-to-get-rid-of-ants-in-the-house-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/10/how-to-get-rid-of-ants-in-the-house-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/10/how-to-get-rid-of-ants-in-the-house-1536x864.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/10/how-to-get-rid-of-ants-in-the-house-640x360.jpg 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/10/how-to-get-rid-of-ants-in-the-house.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p>Ants in your house can be a big nuisance. Here are some really effective <a href="/tag/home-remedies-to-get-rid-of-ants/">home remedies to get rid of ants</a>. They are simple and cost effective.</p>
<p>Where there is one ant visible, there are likely thousands more nearby. If an ant infestation occurs in your home, you’ll want to solve the problem fast.</p>
<h3>Are ants harmful to human ?</h3>
<p>According to the National Wildlife Federation, there are more than <a class="content-link css-5r4717" href="https://www.nwf.org/Educational-Resources/Wildlife-Guide/Invertebrates/Ants" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">12,000 species</a> of ants around the world. Most of these ants are harmless to human.</p>
<p>But ants can carry bacteria, making them potential transmitters of disease or infection. <em>Monomorium</em> ants can carry pathogenic bacteria, which can be dangerous to people. The pharaoh ant, which is a type of <em>Monomorium</em> ant, may be a cause of bronchial asthma and respiratory allergies.</p>
<p>We all hate how ants enter our houses, especially in summers. They live in our house like they own it; well there are some ways that may help to get rid of the ants; one of them is to keep your house absolutely clean. We suggest some amazing home remedies that you&#8217;d need right now to ensure there are no ants in your house. Here&#8217;s how you can get rid of ants at home.</p>
<h2><strong>How to get rid of ants without killing them</strong></h2>
<h3>This is how to <a href="/tag/get-rid-of-ants-permanently/">get rid of ants permanently</a> / Easy ways to repel ants</h3>
<h3> 1. Ground black or red pepper</h3>
<p>Black or red (cayenne) pepper is a natural ant deterrent, as the insects appear to find the smell irritating.</p>
<p>To use this method, sprinkle pepper around baseboards and behind appliances. Anecdotal evidence suggests that this is a safe way to help keep ants at bay.</p>
<h3><strong>2. Chalk</strong></h3>
<p>One of the home remedies to get rid of ants is to use chalk. Chalk contains calcium carbonate, which helps in keeping ants away. Spray some powdered chalk in the areas that are the entry points of ants or draw a line of chalk at the entrance. In order to keep ants of your house, draw chalk lines so that these bugs don&#8217;t enter.</p>
<h3>3. Diatomaceous earth (silicon dioxide)</h3>
<p>Diatomaceous earth is a type of silica made of fossilized remains of aquatic organisms called diatoms (a type of plankton).</p>
<p>Diatomaceous earth isn’t a poison. It kills ants and other bugs by absorbing the oils in their skeletons, which dries them out.</p>
<h3><strong>4. Lemons</strong></h3>
<p>Squeeze a lemon or place lemon peels in places from where the ants enter. You can also wash your floors with water that has a little lemon juice added to it. Ants apparently don&#8217;t like the smell of lemon juice so they will keep away.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1153" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/lemon_620x330.jpg" alt="How to get rid of ants: Squeeze a lemon or place lemon peels in places from where the ants enter" width="620" height="330" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/lemon_620x330.jpg 620w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/10/lemon_620x330-300x160.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 620px) 100vw, 620px" /></p>
<h3>5. Glass cleaner &#8211; liquid detergent</h3>
<p>Ants leave a scented pheromone trail behind when they walk, which acts as a map. This method can remove the scent and deter the ants from reentering your home.</p>
<p>Here is how to do it:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Mix glass cleaning spray with liquid detergent (dish soap) into a clean spray bottle.</li>
<li>Spray the mixture on areas where ants seem to enter from or congregate around.</li>
<li>After spraying, wipe down the area leaving a light residue.</li>
<li>Repeat the above steps as often as needed.</li>
</ol>
<h3><strong>6. Salt</strong></h3>
<p>Spreading salt near nooks and corners from where ants enter the house will help keeping ants away. Table salt is one of the best and the cheapest ways to get rid of ants naturally. Use ordinary table salt not health boosting rock salt. All you need to do is to boil water and add a large amount of salt to it, stirring it until dissolves. Pour into a spray bottle and spray where you think ants tend to enter from.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1156" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/salt-620_620x350.jpg" alt="How to Get Rid of Ants: 8 Home Remedies That Do the TrickLet's face it, ants in your house can be a big nuisance. Here are some really effective home remedies to get rid of ants. They are simple and cost effective.हिंदी में पढ़ेंதமிழில் படிக்கDeeksha KumarUpdated: November 24, 2020 12:20 IST 9 How to Get Rid of Ants: 8 Home Remedies That Do the Trick Ants can be a menace at home, and here are some ways to get rid of them.HighlightsLet's face it, ants in your house can be a big nuisanceHere are some home remedies to get rid of ants instantlyFrom chalk and salt to black pepper, cinnamon and more Let's face it, ants in your house can be a big nuisance. It's not only frustrating to have ants running around, but a colony of ants can actually cause a lot of damage as well. It is pretty unhygienic to have ants inside your home. Some ant varieties like Fire and Harvester can even bite humans. Carpenter ants, on the other hand, are known to damage building materials. Ants inside the house certainly contaminate the food. They carry bacteria which they can transfer to food or an open wound. Ants have a diverse family; they are around 12,000 different varieties of ants. We all hate how ants enter our houses, especially in summers. They live in our house like they own it; well there are some ways that may help to get rid of the ants; one of them is to keep your house absolutely clean. We suggest some amazing home remedies that you'd need right now to ensure there are no ants in your house. Here's how you can get rid of ants at home. Here's how to get rid of ants at home:This is how to get rid of ants permanently-1. ChalkOne of the home remedies to get rid of ants is to use chalk. Chalk contains calcium carbonate, which helps in keeping ants away. Spray some powdered chalk in the areas that are the entry points of ants or draw a line of chalk at the entrance. In order to keep ants of your house, draw chalk lines so that these bugs don't enter. While it not clear as to why this line stops the ants from coming inside, but it is surely effective. Make sure you make the line in a way that is out of reach of any child in the house. 2. LemonsSqueeze a lemon or place lemon peels in places from where the ants enter. You can also wash your floors with water that has a little lemon juice added to it. Ants apparently don't like the smell of lemon juice so they will keep away. Anything sour and bitter may keep the ants away, but any sugar is ants' best friend. So ensure you do not keep anything sweet that may attract the ants in some way or the other. Keep your kitchen slab absolutely clean and place the peels right there. (Also Read: Effective Home Remedies For Sinus To Get Relief) lemon How to get rid of ants: Squeeze a lemon or place lemon peels in places from where the ants enter. Image credits: iStock3. OrangesOranges are same as lemons; they keep the ants away from visiting your house. Make a paste of one cup warm water and a few orange peel, which will help in getting rid of ants. Spread this paste around entry points of ants and wipe it afterwards. You can also place orange peels on the kitchen slab or wherever you think these ants may enter from. It acts as natural deterrent for ants that may not only keep them but also keep them away. So, bring the orange rinds to some use and ensure no ants visit your house anymore. (Also Read: 5 Effective Remedies for Swollen Feet) oranges How to get rid of ants: Oranges are same as lemons; they keep the ants away from visiting your house. Image credits: iStock4. PepperAnts are pretty fond of sugar but they hate pepper. Sprinkle pepper at the areas from where ants enter your house. This is will help getting rid of ants. Cayenne pepper or black pepper are hated by ants. You can also make a solution of pepper and water and spray it near the entrant areas. The pepper wouldn't kill the ants but definitely deter them from returning to your house. Make sure you clean the area where you want to spray the pepper solution. (Also Read: How to Stop Hiccups: Natural Home Remedies) black pepper 625 How to get rid of ants: Ants are pretty fond of sugar but they hate pepper. Image credits: iStock5. SaltSpreading salt near nooks and corners from where ants enter the house will help keeping ants away. Table salt is one of the best and the cheapest ways to get rid of ants naturally. Use ordinary table salt not health boosting rock salt. All you need to do is to boil water and add a large amount of salt to it, stirring it until dissolves. Pour into a spray bottle and spray where you think ants tend to enter from. salt 620 How to get rid of ants: Spread salt near nooks and corners from where ants enter the house" width="620" height="350" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/salt-620_620x350.jpg 620w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/10/salt-620_620x350-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 620px) 100vw, 620px" /></p>
<h3>7. Tea tree oil</h3>
<p>Like peppermint oil, tea tree oil can be an effective ant deterrent. To use this method, complete the following steps:</p>
<ul>
<li>Mix 5 to 10 drops tea tree essential oil with 2 cups water in a clean plastic spray bottle.</li>
<li>Spray the mixture around the house where you typically see ants. Alternatively, you can saturate cotton balls with the mixture and place them around your home.</li>
</ul>
<p>Note: If the scent is too strong, try making a mixture of tea tree oil, peppermint oil, and water.</p>
<p>Like most essential oils, keep tea tree oil out of reach of pets.</p>
<h3><strong>8. White Vinegar</strong></h3>
<p>Ants can&#8217;t bear the smell of white vinegar. Prepare a solution of equal amounts of water and white vinegar. Add a few drops of essential oil to it and shake well. Store this solution and sprinkle it at the points from where the ants enter. Repeat this once daily. Again, this solution may not kill the ants, but definitely keep them away from entering the no-entering zone.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1159" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/vinegar-625_625x350.jpg" alt="How to get rid of ants: Ants can't bear the smell of white vinegar" width="625" height="350" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/vinegar-625_625x350.jpg 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/10/vinegar-625_625x350-300x168.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" /></p>
<h3>9. Coffee grounds</h3>
<p>Brewed coffee grounds have been found to detract ants. Try sprinkling the freshly brewed coffee grounds on disposable surfaces (such as index cards) and leaving them in areas where ants congregate, such as pet bowls.</p>
<p>You can also place the grounds on windowsills. The grounds may lose their potency once they’re dry, so make sure to change often.</p>
<h3>10. Check your houseplants</h3>
<p>Check your houseplants for swarms of ants, which might indicate nests underneath the soil. Discard any plants that appear to be infested.</p>
<p>To stop ants from making homes in your plants, surround the soil with citrus rinds from lemons or oranges.</p>
<h3><strong>11. Peppermint</strong></h3>
<p>Peppermint is an insect repellent, which can help you get rid of ants. Ants don&#8217;t like the smell of peppermint and are likely to avoid areas that contain traces of it. Peppermint has a strong fragrant that cannot be tolerated by the ants, which keep them away from entering the home. Prepare a mixture of 10 drops of peppermint essential oil and a cup of water and sprinkle it wherever you find ants. Repeat this twice a day.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1162" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/peppermint-oil_620x350.jpg" alt="How to get rid of ants: Peppermint is an insect repellent, which can help you get rid of ants" width="620" height="350" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/peppermint-oil_620x350.jpg 620w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/10/peppermint-oil_620x350-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 620px) 100vw, 620px" /></p>
<h3>12. Keep the outdoors outside</h3>
<p>Keep your yard clean of debris. Cut off any vines or vegetation that touches or leans onto the exterior walls of your house and windows that can make it easier for ants to enter your home.</p>
<h3><strong>13. Cinnamon</strong></h3>
<p>Put cinnamon and cloves on the entrance of the house and the areas from where you think the ants can enter. This a good method to also keep your house smelling fresh and earthy. Cinnamon is often regarded as an effective DIY ant control option. It is believed that cinnamon acts as a natural repellent as ants can&#8217;t stand strong smell.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1163" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/cinnamon-625_625x350.jpg" alt="How to get rid of ants: Put cinnamon and cloves on the entrance of the house" width="625" height="350" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/cinnamon-625_625x350.jpg 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/10/cinnamon-625_625x350-300x168.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" /></p>
<h3>14. Eliminate ant entrances</h3>
<p>Figuring out how ants are entering your home can help you eliminate an ant infestation and prevent a future one. Check your home for cracks in the walls and holes near floorboards and radiators. You can seal cracks or treat them with ant repellent. Also, check for rips in window screens that require mending.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>How to stop kitchen ants</h2>
<p>The kitchen, offering proximity to an ample food supply, is often the place that most often attracts ants and other pests. To discourage ants from being in the kitchen:</p>
<ul>
<li>Clean kitchen surfaces and floors every day.</li>
<li>Wash dishes immediately after using them.</li>
<li>Rinse pet food bowls after your dog or cat eats.</li>
<li>Use natural repellents (see examples above) to detract ants and remove the pheromone scent.</li>
<li>Store food properly in sealed containers or bags that lock.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Ants are common invaders of homes across the United States and are mostly harmless. They can be hard to get rid of, but it is possible to repel and eradicate ants over time using the natural methods described above. Commercial products are also available to help kill or detract these pests.</p>
<p>Keeping your home clean and removing possible places for ants to enter and hide can prevent future infestations.</p>
<p>Also read:</p>
<p><a href="/natural-remedies-to-get-rid-of-dark-spots-on-face-neck/">How to get rid of dark spots on face/neck &#8211; Natural remedies</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/get-rid-of-ants-ways-to-repel-ants-safely/">How to Get Rid of Ants : Ways to Repel Ants safely</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">How To Do Stuff</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
