<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>remove a lens Archives - How To Do Stuff</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/remove-a-lens/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/remove-a-lens/</link>
	<description>How To Do Tips and Tricks - How stuff works</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 13:04:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>remove a lens Archives - How To Do Stuff</title>
	<link>/tag/remove-a-lens/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to get a lost or stuck contact lens out of your eye</title>
		<link>/get-a-lost-or-stuck-contact-lens-behind-eye/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=get-a-lost-or-stuck-contact-lens-behind-eye</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Expert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 09:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Eye Care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eye Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bit of contact lens stuck in eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[can contact lens get lost in eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[can contacts get stuck in the back of your eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contact lens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contact lens stuck in eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contact lens stuck on eyeball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contacts getting stuck behind eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gas permeable contact lens stuck in eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[get contact lens out of eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[get contacts from behind eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how do you get a lost contact out of your eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to get a contact out from behind your eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to get a contact out that is behind your eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to get a lost contact lens out of your eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to get a lost contact out of eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to get a lost contact out of my eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to get a lost contact out of your eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to get a stuck contact out of your eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to get contact out from behind eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to get contact out of eye stuck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to get contact stuck behind eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to get contact unstuck from eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to get contacts out when stuck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to get lost contact out of eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to get stuck contact out of eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to remove a lost contact lens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to remove a stuck gas permeable contact lens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to remove contact lens stuck behind eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to remove lens stuck in eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prevent contacts getting lost or stuck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remove a lens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remove a stuck gas permeable contact lens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Removing a soft contact lens from your eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Removing a stuck gas permeable contact lens from your eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stuck contact lens]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=128</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to get contacts from behind eye Getting a contact lens stuck in your eye happens occasionally and can be uncomfortable and irritating. Here are some quick and easy solutions to get a lost or stuck contact lens out of your eye. With a little bit of practice, you’ll be able to do it smoothly &#8230; <a href="/get-a-lost-or-stuck-contact-lens-behind-eye/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/get-a-lost-or-stuck-contact-lens-behind-eye/">How to get a lost or stuck contact lens out of your eye</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">How To Do Stuff</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="dvExtractContntArea" class="col-xs-12 col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-12 no-padding mt10">
<h2><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-129 size-large" title="How to get a lost or stuck contact lens out of your eye" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/lens-4818776_1280-1024x682.jpg" alt="How to get a lost or stuck contact lens out of your eye" width="600" height="400" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/lens-4818776_1280-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/03/lens-4818776_1280-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/03/lens-4818776_1280-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/03/lens-4818776_1280-1200x800.jpg 1200w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/03/lens-4818776_1280.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" />How to get contacts from behind eye</h2>
<p>Getting a <a href="/tag/contact-lens/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">contact lens</a> stuck in your eye happens occasionally and can be uncomfortable and irritating. Here are some <strong>quick and easy solutions</strong> to get a lost or stuck contact lens out of your eye.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-xs-12 col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-12 no-padding blog-content-details">
<p>With a little bit of practice, you’ll be able to do it smoothly with no trouble. Here are some common questions regarding getting a <strong>lens stuck in your eye</strong> and how to deal with it.</p>
<p>Also read : <a href="/natural-remedies-to-get-rid-of-dark-spots-on-face-neck/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How to Get Rid of Dark Spots on Face</a></p>
<h2>Why is my contact lens stuck in my eye?</h2>
<p>If you have slept in your lenses or aren’t taking good care of them, the contacts are prone to drying out, leaving the lens stuck to your eyeball. If you fall asleep in your lenses, avoid pulling the lens out right away. Drink a bit of water, rehydrate yourself and let your eye gain a bit of moisture. This will make a contact stuck in eye easier to remove.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>What happens if contacts get stuck in eye?</h2>
<p>The most common misconceptions about contact lenses are that they can get stuck behind your eye. A contact getting stuck behind the eye is not physically possible; your eyelid is structured to prevent any objects from going to the back of your eye.</p>
<p>A contact lens that gets stuck in the eye is usually a soft contact lens rather than a gas permeable lens. However it is possible for both to get stuck and its wise to be aware that removing a soft contact lens is very different to removing a rigid gas permeable lens.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>How do I remove a lens that’s stuck in my eye?</h2>
<p>The first rule about how to remove a contact lens that’s stuck in your eye is not to panic; trying to pry the lens out may cause more discomfort. Wash your hands before attempting to remove the lens, to avoid getting any bacteria from your hands going in your eye and causing an infection.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Removing a soft contact lens from your eye</h2>
<p>Always make sure you wash your hands thoroughly before attempting to remove a stuck contact lens. If the stuck contact lens is centered on your cornea, you can rinse your eye and the contact that&#8217;s stuck with sterile saline or contact lens rewetting drops such as our comfi Drops. Once you have applied the saline solution or eye drops, close your eye and gently massage your eyelid until the lens moves.</p>
<p>On the other hand, if your eyes are watering heavily, that can also make getting lenses out slightly difficult. Gently wipe your tears away, then, as always, before removing your lenses wash your hands thoroughly. Ensure your fingers are completely dry and this will make removing a stuck lens a little easier.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Removing a stuck gas permeable contact lens from your eye</h2>
<p>If you are wearing gas permeable lenses and they get stuck in your eye, you must avoid massaging your eyelid as this can cause abrasion to the eye. Instead, it is recommended that you use a suction cup to pull the lens of your eye gently .</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Can my contact lens get lost in my eye?</h2>
<p>If you think the contact lens is lost in your eye, it’s probably hiding under your upper eyelid. Simply pull it back slightly to have look and use contact lens solution to flush it out.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>What to do if you can&#8217;t remove a stuck contact lens</h2>
<p>If the lens remains after following the above steps, we advise you to seek medical advice from a doctor or an eye specialist. This should be done as soon as possible to prevent any further problems from occurring.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Top tips to prevent contacts getting lost or stuck in your eye</h2>
<p>Unless it is an extended wear lens, never sleep in your contact lenses &#8211; this can limit the oxygen flow to your cornea and dry out your eyes. In addition, you also risk infection.</p>
<p>Always clean your lenses before putting them in and taking them out. Follow a good eye care and contact lens cleaning routine if your wear monthlies or two weekly’s. Make sure you use fresh contact lens solution to prevent the spread of bacteria.</p>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/get-a-lost-or-stuck-contact-lens-behind-eye/">How to get a lost or stuck contact lens out of your eye</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">How To Do Stuff</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
