<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Fastag Archives - How To Do Stuff</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/fastag/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/fastag/</link>
	<description>How To Do Tips and Tricks - How stuff works</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 07:09:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Fastag Archives - How To Do Stuff</title>
	<link>/category/fastag/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to Check Fastag Balance online : Easy steps</title>
		<link>/how-to-check-fastag-balance-steps/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-check-fastag-balance-steps</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Expert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 09:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fastag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Road Rules]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toll payment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Check fastag balance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[check the balance of Fastag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fastag Application]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fastag balance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fastag charge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fastag Charges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fastag check balance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fastag recharge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to check fastag balance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indian Highways Management Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Highway Authority of India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NHAI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NHAI prepaid wallet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steps to check fastag balance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toll payment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=577</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to check Fastag Balance using online / mobile application / SMS The National Highway Authority of India (NHAI) has introduced A toll-free number to check fastag balance easily. You can give a missed call to that number to know fastag balance in your prepaid wallet account. How to Check Balance in Fastag Account : Customer &#8230; <a href="/how-to-check-fastag-balance-steps/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-check-fastag-balance-steps/">How to Check Fastag Balance online : Easy steps</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">How To Do Stuff</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-623 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/how-to-check-fastag-balance.png" alt="Check fastag balance online steps" width="676" height="380" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/how-to-check-fastag-balance.png 676w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/06/how-to-check-fastag-balance-300x169.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 676px) 100vw, 676px" /></h3>
<h3>How to check Fastag Balance using online / mobile application / SMS</h3>
<p>The National Highway Authority of India (<a href="/tag/nhai/">NHAI</a>) has introduced A toll-free number to <a href="/tag/check-fastag-balance/">check fastag balance</a> easily. You can give a missed call to that number to <strong>know fastag balance</strong> in your prepaid wallet account.</p>
<h3>How to Check Balance in Fastag Account : Customer Care Helpline Number</h3>
<p>If you are a prepaid FASTag customer and have registered your mobile number with the prepaid wallet of the National Highways Authority of India (NHAI), you can know your balance by giving a missed call to the toll-free number: +91-8884333331. This is available 24&#215;7.</p>
<h3>Steps to Check Fastag Balance online using website:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Visit the website of your issuer agency/bank/mobile wallet.</li>
<li>Log into the FASTag portal on the website with your login credentials</li>
<li>You can now view your balance details</li>
</ul>
<p>A Missed Call Alert Facility has been issued by Indian Highways Management Company Ltd which is promoted by NHAI i.e National Highway Authority of India to check the balance of Fastag.</p>
<h3>Fastag Balance check using SMS:</h3>
<p>Once you have opened your FASTag account and linked your mobile number to it, updates will be sent via SMS each time a deduction has been made from your account. Details will be sent regarding <strong>your fastag balance</strong>, toll payments, recharge confirmations, and notifications on low balance.</p>
<p>The text message will show up the combined <strong>balance of Fastag</strong>, in case 2 or more vehicles are linked to NHAI prepaid Wallet. So if there is a low balance in the tag of one vehicle, then the alert will be received for that vehicle through SMS.</p>
<p>By following the above-mentioned procedure, you can check the balance of your Fastag.</p>
<p>Also read: <a href="/how-to-affix-fastag-on-car-windshield/">How to paste/stick FASTag on car windshield</a></p>
<h3>FasTag Balance Check FAQ:</h3>
<ol>
<li><strong>Where can I buy a FASTag? </strong>You can buy a FASTag from one of the Point of Sale (PoS) locations at Toll Plazas, any distribution agents, PoS outlets of the NETC Member Banks, and one of the Sales Offices. You can also get it online by applying at one of the respective issuer bank’s websites or the official www.nhai.gov.in website.</li>
<li><strong>How long is a FASTag valid? </strong>FASTag is valid for a period of 5 years from the date of purchase. On the basis of the usage, you will be required to recharge or top up the tag.</li>
<li><strong>What happens to a FASTag if I sell or transfer my car? </strong>It is recommended that you inform the issuing authority of the FASTag about the sale or transfer of your vehicle. This will allow the authority to close the account.</li>
<li><strong>What do I do if I don’t receive my FASTag refund? </strong>If you have not received your refund for your FASTag payment, you can get in touch with your issuing bank and raise the dispute. The bank will look into it and resolve the issue accordingly.</li>
<li><strong>Do I need to get a new FASTag if I relocate to another city? </strong>No, you will not be required to get a new FASTag if you relocate to a different city. FASTags are designed to work across the country in all the toll plazas which are enabled for it. However, if you are shifting cities or states, it is recommended that you get in touch with the respective issuing authority and inform them about the same.</li>
<li><strong>Is it possible to transfer the FASTag if I change my vehicle? </strong>Yes, it is possible to change the registered vehicle number. In case you have changed your vehicle, you can get in touch with the respective issuing authority and request them to tag the new vehicle to the existing FASTag.</li>
<li><strong>What are the charges of obtaining a FASTag? </strong>As per the government mandate published on the basis of the guidelines issued by the MorTH, a maximum of Rs.100 can be charged for issuing a FASTag. However, there are a number of banks which are offering the FASTags for free.</li>
<li><strong>My vehicle recently got stolen. What should I do about my FASTag account? </strong>In case your vehicle gets stolen, you can block the FASTag account linked to it by calling the respective FASTag issuing authority. On calling the customer care number of the issuing authority and providing the required details, the account will be blocked.</li>
</ol>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-check-fastag-balance-steps/">How to Check Fastag Balance online : Easy steps</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">How To Do Stuff</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where And How To Stick/Paste FASTag On Your Vehicle?</title>
		<link>/how-to-paste-fastag-on-car-windshield/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-paste-fastag-on-car-windshield</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Expert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 08:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fastag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NHAI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Road Rules]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Affix FASTag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Affix fastag on car windshield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affix fastag on windshield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best place to paste fastag in car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FASTag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fastag customer care numbers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FasTag FAQ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fastag how to stick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fastag installation guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FasTag installation steps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fastag pasting on car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FASTag sticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to affix fastag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to affix paytm fastag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to affix sbi fastag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to fix fastag in car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to fix fastag on car windshield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to install fastag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to paste fastag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to paste fastag in car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to paste fastag in car paytm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to put fastag on car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to put fastag on windshield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to remove fastag from car windshield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to remove fastag from windshield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to stick fast tag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to stick fastag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How To Use FASTag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NHAI FasTag Guidelines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NHAI FasTag Rules]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paste FASTag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remove fastag from windshield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RFID Tag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toll payment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toll plaza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toll Tax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[where to fix fastag on car windscreen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[where to place fastag in car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[where to put fastag in car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[where to stick fastag in car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[where to stick fastag in car in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[where to stick fastag sticker in car]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=146</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Fastag pasting on car / Where to stick Fastag on windshield How to stick/affix Fastag on car windshield : Fastag Installation Guide FASTag is a device that employs Radio Frequency Identification (RFID) technology for making toll payments directly while the vehicle is in motion. FASTag (RFID Tag) is affixed on the windscreen of the vehicle &#8230; <a href="/how-to-paste-fastag-on-car-windshield/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-paste-fastag-on-car-windshield/">Where And How To Stick/Paste FASTag On Your Vehicle?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">How To Do Stuff</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-148 size-full" title="Where to affix FASTag on car" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/how-to-affix-fastag.jpg" alt="Where to affix FASTag on car" width="768" height="432" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/how-to-affix-fastag.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/03/how-to-affix-fastag-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /></p>
<h2>Fastag pasting on car / Where to stick Fastag on windshield</h2>
<h3>How to stick/affix Fastag on car windshield : Fastag Installation Guide</h3>
<p><a href="/tag/fastag/">FASTag</a> is a device that employs Radio Frequency Identification (RFID) technology for making toll payments directly while the vehicle is in motion. <a href="/tag/fastag/">FASTag</a> (<a href="/tag/rfid-tag/">RFID Tag</a>) is affixed on the windscreen of the vehicle and enables a customer to make the <a href="/tag/toll-payment/">toll payments</a> directly from the account which is linked to FASTag.</p>
<h3 class="cms-block cms-block-heading">Where do you stick the FASTag sticker for toll payment : steps</h3>
<ul class="cms-block cms-block-ul">
<li>Remove the adhesive lining from the <a href="/tag/fastag-sticker/">FASTag sticker</a></li>
<li>Paste the FASTag on the top middle of the windshield from inside the vehicle or behind the rear view mirror</li>
<li>Gently press the sticker on the windshield</li>
<li>Keep the adhesive side of the FASTag sticker facing outside</li>
<li>Do not try to remove or reposition the FASTag sticker once pasted</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="cms-block cms-block-heading"><strong>Things that need to be take care of while installing Fastag :</strong></h3>
<ul class="cms-block cms-block-ul">
<li>Do not paste the FASTag on a dirty or wet glass surface</li>
<li>If the original adhesive is insufficient, then return the FASTag and get it replaced</li>
<li>Do not use cello tape or any other adhesive to affix the FASTag</li>
<li>Do not try to peel off or reposition the FASTag</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Also read :</p>
<p><a href="/how-to-check-fastag-balance-account-steps/">How to Check Fastag Balance : Steps</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-paste-fastag-on-car-windshield/">Where And How To Stick/Paste FASTag On Your Vehicle?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">How To Do Stuff</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
