<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>install php ubuntu 20.04 Archives - How To Do Stuff</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/install-php-ubuntu-20-04/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/install-php-ubuntu-20-04/</link>
	<description>How To Do Tips and Tricks - How stuff works</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:13:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>install php ubuntu 20.04 Archives - How To Do Stuff</title>
	<link>/tag/install-php-ubuntu-20-04/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How To Install Linux, Nginx, MySQL, PHP (LEMP stack)</title>
		<link>/install-linux-nginx-mysql-php-lemp-stack-on-ubuntu/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=install-linux-nginx-mysql-php-lemp-stack-on-ubuntu</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Expert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 08:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud Computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Installation Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LEMP Installation steps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LEMP stack installation guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tutorial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apt install]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[install mysql ubuntu 20.04]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[install php ubuntu 20.04]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LEMP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LEMP installation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mysql]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nginx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PHP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubuntu 20.04]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>LEMP installation : Ubuntu 20.04 This guide demonstrates how to install a LEMP stack on an Ubuntu 20.04 server. The Ubuntu operating system takes care of the first requirement. We will describe how to get the rest of the components up and running. What is LEMP ? The LEMP software stack serves dynamic web pages &#8230; <a href="/install-linux-nginx-mysql-php-lemp-stack-on-ubuntu/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/install-linux-nginx-mysql-php-lemp-stack-on-ubuntu/">How To Install Linux, Nginx, MySQL, PHP (LEMP stack)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">How To Do Stuff</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-154 size-full" title="Install Linux, Nginx, MySQL, PHP (LEMP stack) on Ubuntu" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/How-To-Install-Linux-Nginx-MySQL-PHP-LEMP-stack-on-Ubuntu-18.04-01-1163x608-1.jpg" alt="Install Linux, Nginx, MySQL, PHP (LEMP stack) on Ubuntu" width="1163" height="608" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/How-To-Install-Linux-Nginx-MySQL-PHP-LEMP-stack-on-Ubuntu-18.04-01-1163x608-1.jpg 1163w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/How-To-Install-Linux-Nginx-MySQL-PHP-LEMP-stack-on-Ubuntu-18.04-01-1163x608-1-300x157.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/How-To-Install-Linux-Nginx-MySQL-PHP-LEMP-stack-on-Ubuntu-18.04-01-1163x608-1-1024x535.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/How-To-Install-Linux-Nginx-MySQL-PHP-LEMP-stack-on-Ubuntu-18.04-01-1163x608-1-768x401.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/How-To-Install-Linux-Nginx-MySQL-PHP-LEMP-stack-on-Ubuntu-18.04-01-1163x608-1-800x418.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 1163px) 100vw, 1163px" /></p>
<h3>LEMP installation : Ubuntu 20.04</h3>
<p>This guide demonstrates how to install a <a href="/tag/lemp/">LEMP</a> stack on an <a href="/tag/ubuntu-20-04/">Ubuntu 20.04</a> server. The Ubuntu operating system takes care of the first requirement. We will describe how to get the rest of the components up and running.</p>
<h3 id="introduction">What is LEMP ?</h3>
<p>The LEMP software stack serves dynamic web pages and web applications written in PHP. This is an acronym that describes a <strong>L</strong>inux operating system, with an Nginx (pronounced like “<strong>E</strong>ngine-X”) web server. The <strong>M</strong>ySQL database  stores backend data and <strong>P</strong>HP handles the dynamic processing.</p>
<h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites</h2>
<p>In order to complete this tutorial, you will need access to an Ubuntu 20.04 server as a regular, non-root <code>sudo</code> user, and a firewall enabled on your server. To set this up, you can follow our initial server setup guide for <a href="/tag/ubuntu-20-04/">Ubuntu 20.04</a>.</p>
<h2 id="step-1-–-installing-the-nginx-web-server">Step 1 – Installing the Nginx Web Server</h2>
<p>In order to display web pages to our site visitors, we are going to employ <a href="/tag/nginx/">Nginx</a>, a high-performance web server. We’ll use the <code>apt</code> package manager to obtain this software.</p>
<p>Since this is our first time using <code>apt</code> for this session, start off by updating your server’s package index. Following that, you can use <code>apt install</code> to get Nginx installed:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> <span class="token function">apt</span> update</li>
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> <span class="token function">apt</span> <span class="token function">install</span> nginx</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<p>When prompted, enter <code>Y</code> to confirm that you want to install Nginx. The Nginx web server will be active and running on your Ubuntu 20.04 server, after the installation is complete.</p>
<p>If you have the <code>ufw</code> firewall enabled, as recommended in our initial server setup guide, you will need to allow connections to Nginx. Nginx registers a few different UFW application profiles upon installation. To check which UFW profiles are available, run:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> ufw app list</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="secondary-code-label " title="Output">Output</div>
<pre class="code-pre "><code>Available applications:
  Nginx Full
  Nginx HTTP
  Nginx HTTPS
  OpenSSH
</code></pre>
<p>You should enable the most restrictive profile. It will still allow the traffic you need. Since you haven’t configured SSL for your server in this guide, you will only need to allow regular HTTP traffic on port <code>80</code>.</p>
<p>Enable this by typing:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> ufw allow <span class="token string">&#8216;Nginx HTTP&#8217;</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<p>You can verify the change by running:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> ufw status</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<p>This command’s output will show that HTTP traffic is now allowed:</p>
<div class="secondary-code-label " title="Output">Output</div>
<pre class="code-pre "><code>Status: active

To                         Action      From
--                         ------      ----
OpenSSH                    ALLOW       Anywhere
<span class="highlight">Nginx HTTP                 ALLOW       Anywhere</span>
OpenSSH (v6)               ALLOW       Anywhere (v6)
<span class="highlight">Nginx HTTP (v6)            ALLOW       Anywhere (v6)</span>
</code></pre>
<p>With the new firewall rule added, you can test if the server is up and running by accessing your server’s domain name or public IP address in your web browser.</p>
<p>If you do not have a domain name pointed at your server and you do not know your server’s public IP address, you can find it by running the following command:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">ip</span> addr show eth0 <span class="token operator">|</span> <span class="token function">grep</span> inet <span class="token operator">|</span> <span class="token function">awk</span> <span class="token string">&#8216;{ print <span class="token variable">$2</span>; }&#8217;</span> <span class="token operator">|</span> <span class="token function">sed</span> <span class="token string">&#8216;s/\/.*$//&#8217;</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>This will print out a few IP addresses. You can try each of them in turn in your web browser.</p>
<p>As an alternative, you can check which IP address is accessible, as viewed from other locations on the internet:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">curl</span> -4 icanhazip.com</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Type the address that you receive in your web browser and it will take you to Nginx’s default landing page:</p>
<pre class="code-pre "><code>http://<span class="highlight">server_domain_or_IP</span>
</code></pre>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://assets.digitalocean.com/articles/lemp_ubuntu2004/nginx_default.png" alt="Nginx default page" /></p>
<p>If you see this page, it means you have successfully installed Nginx and enabled HTTP traffic for your web server.</p>
<h2 id="step-2-—-installing-mysql">Step 2 — Installing MySQL</h2>
<p>Now that you have a web server up and running, you need to install the database system to be able to store and manage data for your site. MySQL is a popular database management system used within PHP environments.</p>
<p>Again, use <code>apt</code> to acquire and install this software:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> <span class="token function">apt</span> <span class="token function">install</span> mysql-server</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>When prompted, confirm installation by typing <code>Y</code>, and then <code>ENTER</code>.</p>
<p>When the installation is finished, it’s recommended that you run a security script that comes pre-installed with MySQL. This script will remove some insecure default settings and lock down access to your database system. Start the interactive script by running:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> mysql_secure_installation</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>This will ask if you want to configure the <code>VALIDATE PASSWORD PLUGIN</code>.</p>
<p><span class="note"><strong>Note:</strong> Enabling this feature is something of a judgment call. If enabled, passwords which don’t match the specified criteria will be rejected by MySQL with an error. It is safe to leave validation disabled, but you should always use strong, unique passwords for database credentials.<br />
</span></p>
<p>Answer <code>Y</code> for yes, or anything else to continue without enabling.</p>
<pre class="code-pre "><code>VALIDATE PASSWORD PLUGIN can be used to test passwords
and improve security. It checks the strength of password
and allows the users to set only those passwords which are
secure enough. Would you like to setup VALIDATE PASSWORD plugin?

Press y|Y for Yes, any other key for No:
</code></pre>
<p>If you answer “yes”, you’ll be asked to select a level of password validation. Keep in mind that if you enter <code>2</code> for the strongest level, you will receive errors when attempting to set any password which does not contain numbers, upper and lowercase letters, and special characters, or which is based on common dictionary words.</p>
<pre class="code-pre "><code>There are three levels of password validation policy:

LOW    Length &gt;= 8
MEDIUM Length &gt;= 8, numeric, mixed case, and special characters
STRONG Length &gt;= 8, numeric, mixed case, special characters and dictionary              file

Please enter 0 = LOW, 1 = MEDIUM and 2 = STRONG: <span class="highlight">1</span>
</code></pre>
<p>Regardless of whether you chose to set up the <code>VALIDATE PASSWORD PLUGIN</code>, your server will next ask you to select and confirm a password for the MySQL <strong>root</strong> user. This is not to be confused with the <strong>system root</strong>. The <strong>database root</strong> user is an administrative user with full privileges over the database system. Even though the default authentication method for the MySQL root user dispenses the use of a password, <strong>even when one is set</strong>, you should define a strong password here as an additional safety measure. We’ll talk about this in a moment.</p>
<p>If you enabled password validation, you’ll be shown the password strength for the root password you just entered and your server will ask if you want to continue with that password. If you are happy with your current password, enter <code>Y</code> for “yes” at the prompt:</p>
<pre class="code-pre "><code>Estimated strength of the password: <span class="highlight">100</span> 
Do you wish to continue with the password provided?(Press y|Y for Yes, any other key for No) : <span class="highlight">y</span>
</code></pre>
<p>For the rest of the questions, press <code>Y</code> and hit the <code>ENTER</code> key at each prompt. This will remove some anonymous users and the test database, disable remote root logins, and load these new rules so that MySQL immediately respects the changes you have made.</p>
<p>When you’re finished, test if you’re able to log in to the MySQL console by typing:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> mysql</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>This will connect to the MySQL server as the administrative database user <strong>root</strong>, which is inferred by the use of <code>sudo</code> when running this command. You should see output like this:</p>
<div class="secondary-code-label " title="Output">Output</div>
<pre class="code-pre "><code>Welcome to the MySQL monitor.  Commands end with ; or \g.
Your MySQL connection id is 22
Server version: 8.0.19-0ubuntu5 (Ubuntu)

Copyright (c) 2000, 2020, Oracle and/or its affiliates. All rights reserved.

Oracle is a registered trademark of Oracle Corporation and/or its
affiliates. Other names may be trademarks of their respective
owners.

Type 'help;' or '\h' for help. Type '\c' to clear the current input statement.

mysql&gt; 
</code></pre>
<p>To exit the MySQL console, type:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px 0px 0px -5px; padding: 0px; list-style: outside none none; white-space: pre;" data-prefix="mysql&gt;"><span class="token builtin class-name">exit</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Notice that you didn’t need to provide a password to connect as the <strong>root</strong> user, even though you have defined one when running the <code>mysql_secure_installation</code> script. That is because the default authentication method for the administrative MySQL user is <code>unix_socket</code> instead of <code>password</code>. Even though this might look like a security concern at first, it makes the database server more secure because the only users allowed to log in as the <strong>root</strong> MySQL user are the system users with sudo privileges connecting from the console or through an application running with the same privileges. In practical terms, that means you won’t be able to use the administrative database <strong>root</strong> user to connect from your PHP application. Setting a password for the <strong>root</strong> MySQL account works as a safeguard, in case the default authentication method is changed from <code>unix_socket</code> to <code>password</code>.</p>
<p>For increased security, it’s best to have dedicated user accounts with less expansive privileges set up for every database, especially if you plan on having multiple databases hosted on your server.</p>
<p><span class="note"><strong>Note:</strong> At the time of this writing, the native MySQL PHP library <code>mysqlnd</code> <a href="https://www.php.net/manual/en/ref.pdo-mysql.php">doesn’t support</a> <code>caching_sha2_authentication</code>, the default authentication method for MySQL 8. For that reason, when creating database users for PHP applications on MySQL 8, you’ll need to make sure they’re configured to use <code>mysql_native_password</code> instead. We’ll demonstrate how to do that in Step 6.<br />
</span></p>
<p>Your MySQL server is now installed and secured. Next, we’ll install PHP, the final component in the LEMP stack.</p>
<h2 id="step-3-–-installing-php">Step 3 – Installing PHP</h2>
<p>You have Nginx installed to serve your content and MySQL installed to store and manage your data. Now you can install PHP to process code and generate dynamic content for the web server.</p>
<p>While Apache embeds the PHP interpreter in each request, Nginx requires an external program to handle PHP processing and act as a bridge between the PHP interpreter itself and the web server. This allows for a better overall performance in most PHP-based websites, but it requires additional configuration. You’ll need to install <code>php-fpm</code>, which stands for “PHP fastCGI process manager”, and tell Nginx to pass PHP requests to this software for processing. Additionally, you’ll need <code>php-mysql</code>, a PHP module that allows PHP to communicate with MySQL-based databases. Core PHP packages will automatically be installed as dependencies.</p>
<p>To install the <code>php-fpm</code> and <code>php-mysql</code> packages, run:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> <span class="token function">apt</span> <span class="token function">install</span> php-fpm php-mysql</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>When prompted, type <code>Y</code> and <code>ENTER</code> to confirm installation.</p>
<p>You now have your PHP components installed. Next, you’ll configure Nginx to use them.</p>
<h2 id="step-4-—-configuring-nginx-to-use-the-php-processor">Step 4 — Configuring Nginx to Use the PHP Processor</h2>
<p>When using the Nginx web server, we can create <em>server blocks</em> (similar to virtual hosts in Apache) to encapsulate configuration details and host more than one domain on a single server. In this guide, we’ll use <strong>your_domain</strong> as an example domain name. To learn more about setting up a domain name with DigitalOcean, see our introduction to DigitalOcean DNS.</p>
<p>On Ubuntu 20.04, Nginx has one server block enabled by default and is configured to serve documents out of a directory at <code>/var/www/html</code>. While this works well for a single site, it can become difficult to manage if you are hosting multiple sites. Instead of modifying <code>/var/www/html</code>, we’ll create a directory structure within <code>/var/www</code> for the <strong>your_domain</strong> website, leaving <code>/var/www/html</code> in place as the default directory to be served if a client request doesn’t match any other sites.</p>
<p>Create the root web directory for <strong>your_domain</strong> as follows:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> <span class="token function">mkdir</span> /var/www/<span class="highlight">your_domain</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Next, assign ownership of the directory with the $USER environment variable, which will reference your current system user:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> <span class="token function">chown</span> -R <span class="token environment constant">$USER</span><span class="token builtin class-name">:</span><span class="token environment constant">$USER</span> /var/www/<span class="highlight">your_domain</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Then, open a new configuration file in Nginx’s <code>sites-available</code> directory using your preferred command-line editor. Here, we’ll use <code>nano</code>:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> <span class="token function">nano</span> /etc/nginx/sites-available/<span class="highlight">your_domain</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>This will create a new blank file. Paste in the following bare-bones configuration:</p>
<div class="code-label " title="/etc/nginx/sites-available/your_domain">/etc/nginx/sites-available/your_domain</div>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<pre class="code-pre language-bash"><code class="code-highlight language-bash">server <span class="token punctuation">{</span>
    listen <span class="token number">80</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span>
    server_name <span class="highlight">your_domain</span> www.<span class="highlight">your_domain</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span>
    root /var/www/<span class="highlight">your_domain</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span>

    index index.html index.htm index.php<span class="token punctuation">;</span>

    location / <span class="token punctuation">{</span>
        try_files <span class="token variable">$uri</span> <span class="token variable">$uri</span>/ <span class="token operator">=</span><span class="token number">404</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span>
    <span class="token punctuation">}</span>

    location ~ <span class="token punctuation">\</span>.php$ <span class="token punctuation">{</span>
        include snippets/fastcgi-php.conf<span class="token punctuation">;</span>
        fastcgi_pass unix:/var/run/php/php7.4-fpm.sock<span class="token punctuation">;</span>
     <span class="token punctuation">}</span>

    location ~ /<span class="token punctuation">\</span>.ht <span class="token punctuation">{</span>
        deny all<span class="token punctuation">;</span>
    <span class="token punctuation">}</span>

<span class="token punctuation">}</span></code></pre>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Here’s what each of these directives and location blocks do:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>listen</code> — Defines what port Nginx will listen on. In this case, it will listen on port <code>80</code>, the default port for HTTP.</li>
<li><code>root</code> — Defines the document root where the files served by this website are stored.</li>
<li><code>index</code> — Defines in which order Nginx will prioritize index files for this website. It is a common practice to list <code>index.html</code> files with a higher precedence than <code>index.php</code> files to allow for quickly setting up a maintenance landing page in PHP applications. You can adjust these settings to better suit your application needs.</li>
<li><code>server_name</code> — Defines which domain names and/or IP addresses this server block should respond for. <strong>Point this directive to your server’s domain name or public IP address.</strong></li>
<li><code>location /</code> — The first location block includes a <code>try_files</code> directive, which checks for the existence of files or directories matching a URI request. If Nginx cannot find the appropriate resource, it will return a 404 error.</li>
<li><code>location ~ \.php$</code> — This location block handles the actual PHP processing by pointing Nginx to the <code>fastcgi-php.conf</code> configuration file and the <code>php7.4-fpm.sock</code> file, which declares what socket is associated with <code>php-fpm</code>.</li>
<li><code>location ~ /\.ht</code> — The last location block deals with <code>.htaccess</code> files, which Nginx does not process. By adding the <code>deny all</code> directive, if any <code>.htaccess</code> files happen to find their way into the document root ,they will not be served to visitors.</li>
</ul>
<p>When you’re done editing, save and close the file. If you’re using <code>nano</code>, you can do so by typing <code>CTRL+X</code> and then <code>y</code> and <code>ENTER</code> to confirm.</p>
<p>Activate your configuration by linking to the config file from Nginx’s <code>sites-enabled</code> directory:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> <span class="token function">ln</span> -s /etc/nginx/sites-available/<span class="highlight">your_domain</span> /etc/nginx/sites-enabled/</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Then, unlink the default configuration file from the <code>/sites-enabled/</code> directory:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> unlink /etc/nginx/sites-enabled/default</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: If you ever need to restore the default configuration, you can do so by recreating the symbolic link, like this:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> <span class="token function">ln</span> -s /etc/nginx/sites-available/default /etc/nginx/sites-enabled/</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This will tell Nginx to use the configuration next time it is reloaded. You can test your configuration for syntax errors by typing:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> nginx -t</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>If any errors are reported, go back to your configuration file to review its contents before continuing.</p>
<p>When you are ready, reload Nginx to apply the changes:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">sudo</span> systemctl reload nginx</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Your new website is now active, but the web root <code>/var/www/<span class="highlight">your_domain</span></code> is still empty. Create an <code>index.html</code> file in that location so that we can test that your new server block works as expected:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">nano</span> /var/www/<span class="highlight">your_domain</span>/index.html</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Include the following content in this file:</p>
<div class="code-label " title="/var/www/your_domain/index.html">/var/www/your_domain/index.html</div>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<pre class="code-pre language-bash"><code class="code-highlight language-bash"><span class="token operator">&lt;</span>html<span class="token operator">&gt;</span>
  <span class="token operator">&lt;</span>head<span class="token operator">&gt;</span>
    <span class="token operator">&lt;</span>title<span class="token operator">&gt;</span><span class="highlight">your_domain</span> website<span class="token operator">&lt;</span>/title<span class="token operator">&gt;</span>
  <span class="token operator">&lt;</span>/head<span class="token operator">&gt;</span>
  <span class="token operator">&lt;</span>body<span class="token operator">&gt;</span>
    <span class="token operator">&lt;</span>h<span class="token operator"><span class="token file-descriptor important">1</span>&gt;</span>Hello World<span class="token operator">!</span><span class="token operator">&lt;</span>/h<span class="token operator"><span class="token file-descriptor important">1</span>&gt;</span>

    <span class="token operator">&lt;</span>p<span class="token operator">&gt;</span>This is the landing page of <span class="token operator">&lt;</span>strong<span class="token operator">&gt;</span><span class="highlight">your_domain</span><span class="token operator">&lt;</span>/strong<span class="token operator">&gt;</span>.<span class="token operator">&lt;</span>/p<span class="token operator">&gt;</span>
  <span class="token operator">&lt;</span>/body<span class="token operator">&gt;</span>
<span class="token operator">&lt;</span>/html<span class="token operator">&gt;</span></code></pre>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Now go to your browser and access your server’s domain name or IP address, as listed within the <code>server_name</code> directive in your server block configuration file:</p>
<pre class="code-pre "><code>http://<span class="highlight">server_domain_or_IP</span>
</code></pre>
<p>You’ll see a page like this:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://assets.digitalocean.com/articles/lemp_ubuntu2004/landing_page.png" alt="Nginx server block" /></p>
<p>If you see this page, it means your Nginx server block is working as expected.</p>
<p>You can leave this file in place as a temporary landing page for your application until you set up an <code>index.php</code> file to replace it. Once you do that, remember to remove or rename the <code>index.html</code> file from your document root, as it would take precedence over an <code>index.php</code> file by default.</p>
<p>Your LEMP stack is now fully configured. In the next step, we’ll create a PHP script to test that Nginx is in fact able to handle <code>.php</code> files within your newly configured website.</p>
<h2 id="step-5-–testing-php-with-nginx">Step 5 –Testing PHP with Nginx</h2>
<p>Your LEMP stack should now be completely set up. You can test it to validate that Nginx can correctly hand <code>.php</code> files off to your PHP processor.</p>
<p>You can do this by creating a test PHP file in your document root. Open a new file called <code>info.php</code> within your document root in your text editor:</p>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<ul class="prefixed">
<li class="line" data-prefix="$"><span class="token function">nano</span> /var/www/<span class="highlight">your_domain</span>/info.php</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Type or paste the following lines into the new file. This is valid PHP code that will return information about your server:</p>
<div class="code-label " title="/var/www/your_domain/info.php">/var/www/your_domain/info.php</div>
<div class="code-toolbar">
<div class="context">
<pre class="code-pre language-bash"><code class="code-highlight language-bash"><span class="token operator">&lt;</span>?php
phpinfo<span class="token punctuation">(</span><span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span></code></pre>
</div>
<div class="toolbar">
<div class="toolbar-item"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>When you are finished, save and close the file by typing <code>CTRL</code>+<code>X</code> and then <code>y</code> and <code>ENTER</code> to confirm.</p>
<p>You can now access this page in your web browser by visiting the domain name or public IP address you’ve set up in your Nginx configuration file, followed by <code>/info.php</code>:</p>
<pre class="code-pre "><code>http://<span class="highlight">server_domain_or_IP</span>/info.php
</code></pre>
<p>You will see a web page containing detailed information about your server.</p>
<p>Also read : <a href="/back-up-and-restore-a-mysql-database-easy-tutorial/">How to Back Up and Restore a MySQL Database</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/install-linux-nginx-mysql-php-lemp-stack-on-ubuntu/">How To Install Linux, Nginx, MySQL, PHP (LEMP stack)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">How To Do Stuff</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
